

Batista Dominique, Research Software Engineer & Web developer

Passion is what gets you through the hardest times that might otherwise make strong men weak, or make you give up — Neil deGrasse Tyson in *the*

LANGUAGES

French: Native English: Fluent

CONTACT/LINK

batisatdominique@hotmail.com LinkedIn: dominique-batista-7696b093 GitHub: Terazus Mobility: International

LATEST PROJECTS

JSONLDSchema

GitHub - Travis Build -Coveralls - Documentation

JSONShema Documenter

GitHub - Live

JSONShema Compare GitHub

Bioschemas Validator GitHub

ABOUT ME

I am a young developer specialized in creating tools and software for scientific researchers and academics. My current activities focus onto delivering clean, tested and documented open-source code to help structuring metadata over the web. My side activities focus onto producing knowledge and scientific papers as well as representing the team in international conferences. I am passionate with computer (hardware, web), science (biology and physics), video games and much more.

POSITIONS

May 2018 - Today

Research Software and Knowledge Engineer, Oxford e-research Center, University of Oxford

Develop software that help data and software providers to achieve FAIRness (Findable, Accessible, Interoperable and Reusable).

Apply and promote software engineering good practices.

Sept. 2015 - Apr. 2018

Web Engineer, French Institute of Bioinformatics (IFB), CNRS UMS-3601, Paris Create and maintain IFB's website located at www.france-bioinformatique.fr.
Advocate for the French community as ELIXIR France representative in the Bioschemas project. Structuring metadata over the web: SEO, semantic markup, semantic validation and editing.

SKILLS/LANGUAGES

Python

Build a suite of tools to create, compare and merge complex set of JSON-schemas as JSON-LD. Expose functions through a RESTful API.

Libraries/Tools: jinja2, requests, jsonschema, nose, mock, pyopenssl, DeepDiff, mock, xmljson, JSONBender, falcon, gunicorn, flake8, coverage, coveralls

Javascript

Document JSON-Schemas as JSON-LD with a web format. Create dynamic web forms. Libraries/Frameworks: AngularJS, JQuery, hopscotch, AJV

Software Engineering

Continuous integration, unit testing & documentation; SEO

Tools: GitHub, Travis-Cl, Coverage/Coveralls, Sphinx/ReadTheDocs, Google Analytics/Search Console, schema.org

Drupal 7

Full-stack and continuous development of a website through a CMS Languages: PHP, JavaScript, MySQL, Apache, HTML/CSS

EDUCATION

2012-2014

Master degree in Bioinformatics, University of Bordeaux Software Engineering, OOP, Omics, Biostatistics.

2010-2011

Bachelor degree in Physiology, Biochemistry and Neuroscience, Birmingham University ERASMUS exchange program.